# AHMED AFFRAZ

Lahore, Pakistan Portfolio ♦ LinkedIn

## **SUMMARY**

Primarily interested in Computer Vision and Digital Image Processing. So naturally, developed an affinity for High-Performance Computing (HPC). Experience ranges from developing algorithms and hardware for Computer Vision applications, to accelerating algorithms using multi-core CPUs and GPUs. Also interested in Deep Learning, especially Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs). A lifelong gamer and audiophile at heart.

## **SKILLS**

Technical Skills Programming Technologies Computer Vision, Digital Image Processing, High-Performance Computing, Deep Learning C/C++, C#, Matlab, Python, OpenCV, NVIDIA CUDA, OpenMP, OpenCL, TensorFlow Linux, Git, Visual Studio, VS Code

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Computer Vision and HPC Engineer, Purple Gaze

Jun 2022 - Present

- Our team developed a low-cost/high-fps eye-tracking system that processes 700+ fps on embedded devices
- Developed algorithms to improve accuracy and speed of pupil tracking

# Senior CUDA Engineer, Pangu Technologies

Jan 2022 - Jun 2022

- Worked in team of several PhDs to improve Ethereum mining hashrate, based on CUDA
- Achieved speedup of 0.5% of the mining hashrate. This is within 0.5% of one of the best commercial Ethereum miner, T-Rex

# Technical Team Lead, TASC Management

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

- Implemented algorithms for **Jetson Nano using CUDA** to be processed on the edge
- Redesigned the Under Vehicle Inspection System to make it more portable

# Head of Computer Vision, Evolve Innovative Solutions (EIS)

Aug 2019 - Nov 2020

- Developed **cloth simulation/rendering software** to analyze new styles of clothes, using open-source tools. Designed solution saves quite some man hours compared to commercially available software, Tukatech
- $\bullet$  Optimized a photogrammetry rig to produce better results and use %10 fewer cameras

## Technical Team Lead, TASC Management

Apr 2014 - Jul 2019

- Completely developed the hardware and algorithms to perform real-time inspection of the under vehicles. The designed unit is one of the smallest portable unit in the market
- Implemented a real-time, multi-threaded image-stitching algorithm to generate a complete image of under vehicle
- Implemented algorithms to automatically detect foreign objects attached under the vehicles
- Designed the structural and optical parts of the hardware using Autodesk Inventor
- Developed optical simulations in Matlab to minimize size of the hardware and making it portable

## CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

- Deep Learning Specialization by Andrew Ng (Coursera, 2021)
- Introduction to Parallel Programming in CUDA (Udacity, 2013)

# **EDUCATION**